### **Egor Philippov**

E: philippovegor@gmail.com
W: www.egorphilippov.me
G: github.com/hoboman313



#### About Me

I am a dedicated and passionate full stack software engineer specializing in building modern SaaS web applications. My <u>current</u> go-to tech stack is **Ember.js** + **Bootstrap** + **Sass** for the frontend, **Node.js** ( Express.js ) for the middle tier, **NoSQL** ( DynamoDB or MongoDB ) for the backend and deployed via **AWS** ( cloudfront, elastic beanstalk, elasticache - redis, etc.. ). I am actively operating and developing numerous web applications including: <a href="https://www.tomati.io/">https://www.tomati.io/</a> and <a href="https://www.tomati.io/">https://www.tomati.io/</a> and <a href="https://www.huegasm.com/">https://www.huegasm.com/</a>

## Work Experience

#### Fullstack Developer at Google: Nest Labs (via Appnovation)

Remote — Oct. 2016 - Present

Full Stack development for https://enterprise.nest.com/ in Ember.js and golang.

#### Senior Software Engineer, Absolute Software Co.

Vancouver, BC — Jan. 2014 - Oct.2016

Development of various enterprise web applications for remote management of devices with an Ember.js SPA frontend and a Java RESTful API backend.

**Languages/Tools**: Ember.js,Java EE ( Jersey + Spring ), SQLite, MongoDB, Shell scripting, Node scripting, TeamCity, Git, TFS, (a little) C++

#### Accomplishments

- Full stack development utilizing an Ember.js SPA + Java API for numerous b2b products
- Implementation of push notifications for automatic data updates using WebSocket push notifications via the Atmosphere framework
- Creation and deployment of builds through TeamCity
- Management and configuration of a linux-based dev environment
- Analysis and optimization of a production environment for a SaaS product ( https://cc.absolute.com)

#### Intermediate Software Engineer, OpenBet Technologies Ltd.

Burnaby, BC — Aug. 2012 - Jan. 2014

Development for playnow.com, technical analysis of customer requirements.

**Languages/Tools**: TCL, JavaScript (Backbone.js, RequireJS), Informix, Bash scripting, Linux command line

Accomplishments

- Development to allow for operators to manually register players through the back office system
- Worked on the technological analysis for upcoming projects
- Ported the existing backend generated HTML templates to be compiled and rendered using Handlebars
- Developed an architecture for 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendors to be allowed restricted access to the back office system

#### Intern Developer, SAP

Vancouver, BC — Aug. 2009 - Aug. 2010

Bug fixing, troubleshooting, enhancements, new development of the installation software for various company products

Languages/Tools: Java, Perforce, Visual Studio 2005, Eclipse

#### Accomplishments

- Developed and maintained a system for uploading the installed product information to a web server
- Collaboratively worked on an installer for an upcoming new product ( SAP Business Objects Explorer ) with a team from France
- Troubleshot problems pertaining to general installation features
- Improved and maintained existing product installer functionality

# Other Experience & Projects

- A web application for searching the restaurant health inspection reports: https://www.tomati.io ( currently in active development )
- A web application for controlling Philips Hue lights and synchronizing the beat of the user's music with them: <a href="http://www.huegasm.com">http://www.huegasm.com</a>
- Co-taught introductory web development to high school students through BrainStation Vancouver
- Used to develop plugins for a popular game called Counter Strike 1.6. My old, publicly available plugins are still up at:
   <a href="http://www.amxmodx.org/compiler.php?mod=1&cat=0&plugin=&author=hoboman&go=search">http://www.amxmodx.org/compiler.php?mod=1&cat=0&plugin=&author=hoboman&go=search</a>
- I'm probably playing around with something on Github. Find me at <a href="https://github.com/hoboman313">https://github.com/hoboman313</a>

#### Education

#### **Simon Fraser University**

Bachelor of Science in Computing Science — 2009-2012

Concentration in Information Systems

#### **Langara College**

Associate of Science Degree — 2006-2009